<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>anton</title>
    <description>Starting to Jekyll.</description>
    <link>www.anton23.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="www.anton23.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 16:53:53 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 16:53:53 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.1.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I received my blog’s web hosting bill from Amazon Web Services. What
used to be 52 cents have been multiplied 5,300 folds.  I’m guessing a few 
people got hold of my blog and the link was passed around. Hence, now 
I’m switching to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; for support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transition was pretty simple and everything has been pretty straightforward.
I guess it also helped that I’ve used Github in the past and have tinkered with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://middlemanapp.com/&quot;&gt;The Middleman&lt;/a&gt; in my previous web projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transition is not complete yet, but I have a good 85% of it set. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 07:42:59 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/jekyll/update/2014/07/03/learning-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/jekyll/update/2014/07/03/learning-to-jekyll/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strength Training</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progression.&lt;/strong&gt;  This is the most important concept of strength training, and unfortunately the last concept I learned. I wish I learned it before everything else.  It’s been called “progressive overload” or “linear progression” in the strength-training world, but all it means is seeing a progressive pattern overtime.  I kind of stumbled upon it when I finally tuned out of the world and just went on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple example of the progression concept is pull-ups.  If the maximum pull-ups I could do last week was 10 and this week’s was 13, there was progression and it means I’ve developed strength.  It’s also safe to assume that I’ve developed muscle size (albeit very small) because there’s a positive correlation between increase in strength and increase in muscle size.  For this reason, it would make sense to keep track of the progression overtime (i.e. strength) because that would indicate any increase in muscle-size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that amaze me about the human body is how it learns to adapt.  If I squatted 200 lbs today for 4 repetitions, in a couple of days I would be able to increase the repetitions to 6 provided I got regular sleep and nutrition.  Now imagine if I was squatting over the course of 10 months?  How much progress would that be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hazy-period&quot;&gt;The Hazy Period.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s like shooting darts in the dark.&lt;/strong&gt;  When I started lifting, it was not very inspiring.  I would go to the gym and would get some good workout, but I wasn’t seeing any results even after several months of working out.  The good thing that came out of it was that I learned various exercises. The bad thing was that I wasted soo much time as there was no way for me to see where I was in the grand scheme of things.  I was in this period for a long time, and since it did not occur to me to focus on my progression, there’s no data to see other than some random photos taken at arbitrary times.  :/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;imgur-album&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/8uBDi/embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-wave&quot;&gt;The First Wave.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keeping it simple.&lt;/strong&gt; 
When I tuned out of the world, I decided to stop following all the recommended routines I’ve read online, and decided to just focus on my own.  I kept things simple by doing upper and lower body splits.  And since I do enjoy bodyweight exercises, I felt having a calisthenics day too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Routines (In this order):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lower Body Day:
1. &lt;strong&gt;Squats (Low-bar).&lt;/strong&gt; 3 sets.  Max Reps of 8.
2. &lt;strong&gt;Deadlifts.&lt;/strong&gt; 3 sets. Max Reps of 5.
3. &lt;em&gt;A whatever exercise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upper Body Day:
1. &lt;strong&gt;Shoulder Press (Barbell, Standing).&lt;/strong&gt;  3 sets. Max Reps of 8.
2. &lt;strong&gt;Chest Press (Barbell, Flat Bench).&lt;/strong&gt; 3 sets. Max Reps of 10.
4. &lt;em&gt;A whatever exercise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calisthenic Day:
1. Stretching Routine
2. &lt;strong&gt;Pull-up/Chin-up Medley.&lt;/strong&gt; 3 sets each.
3. Dragon Flags. 3 sets.
4. &lt;em&gt;A whatever exercise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Items in &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; are the main exercises, and I kept track of them to see if there’s progression. At first I used my cellphone’s Excel sheet for logging, but I switched to  a notebook as it proved to be more convenient.  All the bolded items when combined together make a complete body workout.  If there’s an exercise that’s a li’l redundant it’s probably chest presses because the upper chest gets activated during shoulder presses already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;whatever exercise&lt;/em&gt; was any exercise that I fancied doing because I was already in the gym and I haven’t even spent a full hour yet, so I might as well do an extra exercise. On days I wouldn’t have time or not feel well, I would skip it.  This was usually some kind of light exercise like calf raises or dumbbell curls.  I did not keep track of the &lt;em&gt;whatever exercise&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s the exercise I allow myself to half-ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I’m not the best logger of all time and I started creating logs in October 2013, and I’m pretty sure I started doing the routine even earlier than that. I did with the routine above for a few months.  There was small progression in the lift’s numbers; however, some noticeable progression on the physique could be seen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;imgur-album&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/kV3sR/embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation.&lt;/strong&gt; In October 2013, I decided to start a monthly check-in and keep an electronic log of my current lifts and photos. I even created my own notation for logging sets and reps with &lt;em&gt;Weight: Rep, Rep, Rep&lt;/em&gt;.  Take the squats entry  in the first photo for example. Before that photo was taken, I squatted 190 lbs with 6 reps for the 1st set, 6 reps for the 2nd set, and 8 reps for the 3rd; hence, 190: 6, 6, 8. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the first set (i.e., 190 lbs at 6 reps) was converted to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One-repetition_maximum&quot;&gt;1 rep max&lt;/a&gt;, it would be “235 1RM”, which I could use to compare with next month’s lift. Think of 1RM as a conversion unit to compare 2 measurements with different units because that’s the only way you can compare lifting 190 lbs at 6 reps vs 185 lbs at 8 reps. The items in the brackets [] are my personal notes.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 2  months of documenting was not really inspiring as I wasn’t seeing much changes.  Once the 3rd month hit, there was some noticeable changes in the photos and lifting logs.  Since then, documenting the monthly progression started to become something I look forward to every month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule on Progression.&lt;/strong&gt; For any of the main exercises, I would do three sets (aka working sets), and in each set  I would shoot for the max reps.  Let’s take squats for example.  If today I lifted 190 lbs for 3 sets with 6, 6, and 8 reps respectively.  This means that when I do squats next time, I would still use the same weight of 190 lbs for 3 sets.  The only time I would increase the weight to 200 lbs is once I hit the max reps of 8 for each set (which might take  a few weeks if I’m consistent enough).  For the lower body, I would increase the weight by 10 lbs; upper body would get 5 lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diet.&lt;/strong&gt; During this period, I was in a very low carb diet, which was almost keto on certain days. Since I was a vagabond (a story for another blog), I would only buy food  to be finished that day.  I would eat about 1.25 lbs of cooked meat from Albertson’s, a bag of vegetables, and 12 hard-boiled eggs.  There would be certain days when I would buy a couple of bananas and yogurt because I felt I needed more calories and they’re cheap.  I would throw in protein powder at times.  With the exception of protein powder and yogurt, all of my caloric intake was paleo.  The chart below shows what typical food items I would eat, and the total calories would average between 2200 - 2600. In addition to all of these, I followed an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intermittent_fasting&quot;&gt;intermittent fasting&lt;/a&gt; way of eating where I typically would eat within an 8 hour window and fast for the other 16 hours of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/HodJd64.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; alt=&quot;Food Log&quot; title=&quot;Food Log&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order of Exercises.&lt;/strong&gt;  The only rule I followed was to always Squat before Deadlift.  All other main exercises could be shuffled.  Also, &lt;em&gt;whatever exercises&lt;/em&gt; must be done after main exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warm-up.&lt;/strong&gt;  The entire point of warm-up is to get use to the motion before doing heavier weight.  I would usually do 1-3 sets of warm-up before a main exercise. The more taxing an exercise (i.e., squats) is, the more sets it would get.  The &lt;em&gt;whatever exercises&lt;/em&gt; and calisthenics did not get warm-up sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resting.&lt;/strong&gt; Rule of thumb was to be aware of my body (queue in meditation here), check if my breathing/heart rate is back to normal, and ensure that my body isn’t about to go cold.  Squats and Deadlifts are the most taxing exercises, and I would find myself resting about 4 minutes between sets.  Shoulder Press and Chest Press took less time, usually about 2 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequency.&lt;/strong&gt; Witht the exceptionof being sick, My rule of thumb was that if I had ample sleep and a couple of square meals, I owe it to my body to do major physical movements.  There were days when I wasn’t able to lift, so I just did calisthenics at home or a nearby playground.  Also, since I do it almosty daily, working out just became part of my normal routine, similar to eating lunch is. My internal discussions if I should workout today, for example, have stopped altogether because my mind knows working out is part of my daily cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-change-up&quot;&gt;The Change Up.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changing the exercise because of injury.&lt;/strong&gt;  Condensing the exercises into two days was not really necessary, and the three-day split I had was fine as it was.  The main change-up was in my style of Squats and Chest Presses because of injury. (The &lt;em&gt;whatever exercise&lt;/em&gt; is now called &lt;em&gt;accessory exercise&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lower-body Day:
1. &lt;strong&gt;Squat (Highbar).&lt;/strong&gt; 3 sets. Max reps of 8.
2. &lt;strong&gt;Deadlifts.&lt;/strong&gt; 3 sets. Max reps of 5.
3. &lt;em&gt;One Accessory Exercise.&lt;/em&gt; 2 sets. Max reps of 13.
4. &lt;em&gt;One Ab Exercise (Dragon Flags).&lt;/em&gt; 2 sets. Max reps of 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upper-body Day:
1. &lt;strong&gt;Pull-up/Chin-up Medley&lt;/strong&gt;. 3 sets (6 total). Max reps of 13.
2. &lt;strong&gt;Shoulder Presses  (Barbell, Standing).&lt;/strong&gt; 3 sets. Max reps of 8.
3. &lt;strong&gt;Chest Presses (Single-arm Dumbbell, Flat bench).&lt;/strong&gt; 3 sets. Maxrep 10.
4. &lt;em&gt;One Accessory Exercise&lt;/em&gt;. 2 sets. Max reps of 13.
5. &lt;em&gt;One Ab Exercise (Dragon Flags).&lt;/em&gt; 2 sets. Max reps of 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Form and Injury.&lt;/strong&gt; It took me several months to figure out my form for various exercises. The more I did an exercise, the more l’d notice the nuances on bodily movements and what muscle group was firing (no surprise here, Sherlock).  It also helped that I video recorded my Squats, Deadlifts, and Shoulder Presses, and then later assessed them myself or asked feedback from reputable online forums with lifting coaches.  As for other learning materials, for Deadlifts, Chest Press, and Shoulder Press, I based them on the book Starting Strength 3rd Edition.  The pull-up/chin-up, I played with it.  I noticed that my back is more activated during a wide grip pull-up and a shoulder-width grip chin-up. I also learned to never lock-out on the bottom of a pull-up/chin-up to prevent shoulder injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I based my squats (low-bar) initially from the Starting Strength book too, but a low-bar style of squats caused  some knee pain; hence, I looked into the high-bar style (aka Ass-To-Grass) squats which is the more natural way of squatting (this is the squat that a toddler naturally does if he was to squat or pick something up from the ground).  I had to start from very light weight again when I switched, so I could learn and critique my form. Once I got hold of the proper motion, I felt at home with the high-bar squat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/l4YPY8p.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; alt=&quot;Natural Squat Form&quot; title=&quot;Natural Squat Form&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have developed some shoulder pain when doing bench press with a barbell.  I switched to dumbbells and it no longer bothers me.  My observation was that barbell puts my arm in a less-natural position (probably due to length and my anatomy, I don’t know).  By switching to dumbbells, my arm has been able to position itself optimally, so I experience no pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, since I’m now doing a different style of squat and chest press now, I had to track them separately from my previous squat and chest press logs (i.e., they’re a different kind of exercises and should not be considered a continuation of the old style.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety.&lt;/strong&gt;  Weight lifting is very safe compared to any other sports (Starting Strength has the stats).  Barbell Bench Press is the only one that has killed and injured people since most people do it with no spotter or a lousy spotter; hence, I recommend to always do it with an attentive spotter.  Squats is very safe provided you use safety pins (I use it all the time); it’s even safer if you know the bail-out technique (I use this too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diet.&lt;/strong&gt; After moving to an apartment, I started preparing meals on the daily.  I incorporated more carbs into my diet because I needed to increase my caloric intake;  I was already satisfying my protein and fat intake, so carb had to increase and the cheapest way was to incorporate white rice.  White rice is not paleo, but it’s gluten-free – which is not a bad tradeoff. My main source of protein was still eggs and animal meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/cMgPDmZ.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; alt=&quot;Food&quot; title=&quot;Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progression.&lt;/strong&gt; The charts below show my progression on the main exercises from my monthly check-ins.  I separated the pull-up/chin-up routine in a different graph because it doesn’t involve added weights.  As I mentioned earlier, Squats and Chest Press have 2 logs each (one for each style) which doesn’t really help to show the overall trend of their progression because of the shorter time period.  Nonetheless, there is a trend that ought to be noticed on the deadlifts, shoulder presses, and pull-up/chin-up – they’re progressing overtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/pxmWAtp.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700px&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; alt=&quot;Food&quot; title=&quot;Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/XRODF2l.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700px&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; alt=&quot;Food&quot; title=&quot;Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/tum7drw.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700px&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; alt=&quot;Food&quot; title=&quot;Food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 07:43:59 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/exercise/2014/06/01/strength-training/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/exercise/2014/06/01/strength-training/</guid>
        
        
        <category>exercise</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Investing... Here we go again.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve looked into investing pretty heavily about 5 years ago.  I wish I made notes of the terms that ought to be remembered and the approach I followed.  Oh well, it’s not too late to refresh my memory and make notes.  So here goes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 2014.  The approach I’ll be using is making my portfolio.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, reading…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I Will Teach You To Be Rich – as far as investing is concerned, you cannot beat the market and you’re better off investing in index funds because of the low fees.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Boglehead’s Guide to Investing&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Random Walk Down Wall Street&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 07:43:59 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/investing/2014/06/01/investing-again/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/investing/2014/06/01/investing-again/</guid>
        
        
        <category>investing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Power Pose: Increasing the T in 2 Minutes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/i8FLwEs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kinesthetic sense.  We’ve constantly trained our brain to focus on what’s in front of our eyes, but many of us fail to develop the ability to recognize what posture our body is in without looking at one’s reflection.  How many times throughout the day have we asked ourselves: &lt;em&gt;“Am I opening up, or is my body hunched down?”&lt;/em&gt;  Opening the body up is a sign of power and is evident in the animal kingdom and human reaction.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Cu6ZFEq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Amy Cuddy’s &lt;em&gt;Ted Talk&lt;/em&gt; presentation she explains that doing a high-power pose for 2-minutes increases testosterone by 20% (and reduces cortisol by 25%).  On the other hand, a low-power pose reduces testosterone by 10% (and increases cortisol by 15%).  In short, one’s bodily posture produces hormones that will alter the mind which alter’s the behavior.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as we all know, high testosterone and low cortisol are directly &lt;a href=&quot;http://health.yahoo.net/experts/dayinhealth/surprising-facts-about-testosterone&quot;&gt;correlated to positive traits&lt;/a&gt; such as confidence, happiness, sharper memory, allure, and many more.  So the next time when you’re sitting at your desk job or texting, ask yourself: “Am I opening-up or hunching down?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/Ks-_Mh1QhMc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 06:43:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/life/exercise/interact/2014/02/27/power-pose/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/life/exercise/interact/2014/02/27/power-pose/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>exercise</category>
        
        <category>interact</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>30 Things I Don&#39;t Ever Want To Be...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I ran into &lt;a href=&quot;http://themanlyrules.com/2014/02/02/30-things-i-dont-ever-want-to-be/&quot;&gt;a blog article about being your own man&lt;/a&gt;.  I thought the content was pretty hilarious and that they rang true, so  I thought maybe I should start crossing ones out as if it were my list…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;A gross fat sweaty mess that sucks the public coffers dry by placing demands on the state because I’m too lazy to manage my own lifestyle.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An apologist for all that passes as acceptable in a society content to celebrate mediocrity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;45 years old, struggling to get and maintain an erection when looking at my pig wife with the consolation of watching some sports team every weekend in a public house full of other losers drinking overpriced poison (with ice) contemplating where it all went wrong whilst deriving a miniscule amount of pleasure/displeasure from said sportsmen who couldn’t give a flying fuck about me. Interspersed by standing outside in the pouring rain and wind chugging on a cancer stick bringing my sad existence ever closer to a painful finale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A whiney bitch who fails to take action whilst complaining about his lot in life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Someone who would rather watch mind-numbing television instead of picking up a book.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Living a lifestyle dominated by a woman that I’m too scared to stand up to.  (Unless I succomb to ‘fear’ #3 above and I’m paying for it.)    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone who can’t relax and is unable to take life on the chin a little and laugh at what the universe throws up every now and again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone who is malnourished and feeds a corrupt ‘health care’ system that is purely run, not to prevent disease, but rather treat symptoms and further the greedy needs of a pharmaceutical industry from top to bottom and pops a multitude of pills just to get through each day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Someone who ashamed to look at himself in the mirror.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constantly worried about money and never experiencing financial freedom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Someone bitterly consumed by politics who shouts political rants at a TV screen as he feels his needs aren’t being met.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scared to face reality and accept life for what it is.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone who needs to attack others for personal gain or a twisted sense of validation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone who seeks validation at all.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a place whereby I feel I need to rely on ‘things’ to impress people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;An habitual user of pornography because I lack human interaction.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘white knight’ who attempts to impress women by sacrificing my masculinity in their honour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lacking in quality friendships and connections.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone who is blind to other people’s standpoints before analysis of them (whether they are ultimately wrong or otherwise).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unable to explain to others why I hold certain viewpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too weak to challenge viewpoints I consider wrong after analysis (see #19).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working a job I hate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Living in a place I hate.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone who has ceased to experience new things and lives a mundane life of repetition.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Unable to enjoy physical exercise befitting of my age.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angry and full of regret.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lacking in depth and being one-dimensional.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addicted to anything other than the simple joy of living.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suffering.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Unable to think of a 30th point for a blog post entitled ’30 Things I Don’t Ever Want To Be…’&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve crossed out a few items that stood out to me as something I’ve successfully trumped at this point. I’ll visit this again in a year’s time and see what other items I feel I’ve conquered.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 06:43:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/life/2014/02/24/i-dont-ever-want-to-be/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/life/2014/02/24/i-dont-ever-want-to-be/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lessons learned from a Hackathon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I attended a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/redesign-a-ux-design-hackathon-tickets-10500873395&quot;&gt;UX Design Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; this past Sunday in Santa Monica.  A few takeaways from my observation… &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Paradox of Choice: Why More Is Less.&lt;/strong&gt;  This paradox applies to design, but it’s funnier when one realizes it applies to forming a team.  The hackathon event started with an hour long breakfast, where participants mingled to form teams.  The good news was that there were more than a hundred participants.  The bad news was that one could be tempted to reach out to all of them – which I did (maybe because it was my default setting).  If I were to talk to each one for one minute, the most I could talk to would be 60 people in one hour.  Hence, I’m sure I wasn’t able to talk to half of them.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A five-hour UX design Hackathon is not enough time.&lt;/strong&gt;  It seemed that everyone was gung-ho about delivering a product.  Each group picked a team meber from each background (e.g., programming, design, UX/UI, etc.) to ensure that all kinds of tasks would get covered – not a bad idea if you ask me.  However, at the end of the day, no one was able to deliver a finished product and all final presentations were PowerPoint slides of theoretical solutions.  It seemed that picking a team member based on skillset wasn’t useful for that five-hour task.  I wonder how the experienced would have been if teams picked their members based on some other criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make it more personal.&lt;/strong&gt;  According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cFdCzN7RYbw&quot;&gt;science of persuasion&lt;/a&gt;, exchanging personal information and identifying similarities before tackling business leads to 90% more agreeable outcomes. My next goal is to make a conscious decision to start  group work like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon was definitely a good way to spend the day.  It made me think about the Psychology of team dynamics and product delivery.  I’ll definitely tweak a few things on my approach the next time I do it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 06:43:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/skills/2014/02/21/lessons-from-hackathon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/skills/2014/02/21/lessons-from-hackathon/</guid>
        
        
        <category>skills</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Be a Leader: How to Change People without Arousing Resentment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/7X70A2c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing-small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Dale Carnegie’s &lt;em&gt;“How to Win Friends and Influence People,”&lt;/em&gt; he noted ways on influencing people. To me these points can be summarized into: creating a friendly atmosphere, nourishing the other person’s self-esteem, and instilling fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. If you must find fault, begin with Praise and Honest Appreciation.&lt;/strong&gt;  “It is always easier to listen to unpleasant things after we have heard some praise of our good points.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Call attention to people’s mistake indirectly.&lt;/strong&gt; Never use “but…” when addressing a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Talk about your own mistakes before criticizing the other person.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;“I concluded that Josephine’s batting average at nineteen was better than mine had been – and that, I’m sorry to confess, isn’t paying Josephine much of a compliment.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Ask questions instead of giving orders.&lt;/strong&gt;  This is principle is best described making the other person be actively involved in creating the solution the situation.  Asking someone, “Are you wrong?” won’t fix the issue, but asking, “What do you think is the best solution” proabably would.  Besides, no one likes to take orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Let the other person save face.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. To Spur People into Success: Praise the slightest improvement and praise every improvement.&lt;/strong&gt;  Be ‘hearty in your approbation and lavish in your praise.’  Animal trainers have been using this technique for ages.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &quot;Use of praise instead of criticism is the basic concept of B. F. Skinner’s teachings. This great contemporary psychologist has shown by experiments with animals and with humans that when criticism is minimized and praise emphasized, the good things people do will be reinforced and the poorer things will atrophy for lack of attention.&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Give the other person a fine reputation to live up to.&lt;/strong&gt;  This becomes an exciting challenge to live up to for anyone.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Make the Fault seem Easy to Correct.&lt;/strong&gt;  Use encouragement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.  Make the other person happy about doing the thing you suggest.&lt;/strong&gt;  The effective leader should keep the following guidelines in mind when it is necessary to change attitudes or behaviour:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be sincere. Do not promise anything that you cannot deliver. Forget about the benefits to yourself and concentrate on the benefits to the other person.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know exactly what it is you want the other person to do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be empathetic. Ask yourself what is it the other person really wants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider the benefits that person will receive from doing what you suggest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Match those benefits to the other person’s wants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you make your request, put it in a form that will convey to the other person the idea that he personally will benefit. We could give a curt order like this: “ John, we have customers coming in tomorrow and I need the stockroom cleaned out. So sweep it out, put the stock in neat piles on the shelves and polish the counter.” Or we could express the same idea by showing John the benefits he will get from doing the task: “John, we have a job that should be completed right away. If it is done now, we won’t be faced with it later. I am bringing some customers in tomorrow to show our facilities. I would like to show them the stockroom, but it is in poor shape. If you could sweep it out, put the stock in neat piles on the shelves, and polish the counter, it would make us look efficient and you will have done your part to provide a good company image.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 06:43:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/interact/2014/01/31/be-a-leader/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/interact/2014/01/31/be-a-leader/</guid>
        
        
        <category>interact</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Win People to Your Way of Thinking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/FfUJnSl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing-small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Dale Carnegie’s &lt;em&gt;“How to Win Friends and Influence People,”&lt;/em&gt; he noted ways on influencing people. To me these points can be summarized into: creating a friendly atmosphere, nourishing the other person’s self-esteem, and instilling fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The only way to get the best of an argument is to avoid it.&lt;/strong&gt;  Case in point: &lt;em&gt;“You can’t win an argument.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Show respect for the other person’s opinions. Never 
tell anyone, “You’re wrong.”&lt;/strong&gt;  This is the sure fire way to avoid making enemies out of people.   It’s also the reason why you cannot change someone’s mind about their religion because it’s an attack to their self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to enlighten someone? There’s magic, positive magic, in such phrases as: “I may be wrong. I frequently am. Let’s examine the facts.”  This increases the probability in your favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&quot;I made it a rule,&quot; said Franklin, &quot;to forbear all direct contradiction to  the sentiment of others, and all positive assertion of my own, I even forbade myself the use of every word or expression in the language that imported a fix&#39;d opinion, such as &#39;certainly,&#39; &#39;undoubtedly,&#39; etc., and I adopted, instead of them, &#39;I conceive,&#39; &#39;I apprehend, &#39; or &#39;I imagine&#39; a thing to be so or so, or &#39;it so appears to me at present.&#39; When another asserted something that I thought an error, I deny&#39;d myself the pleasure of contradicting him abruptly...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. If you’re wrong, admit it quickly and emphatically.”&lt;/strong&gt; Remember the old proverb: &lt;em&gt;“By fighting you never get enough, but by yielding you get more than you expected.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Add a drop of honey.&lt;/strong&gt; Be friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Get the other person saying “yes, yes” immediately.&lt;/strong&gt; The secret of Socrates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Let the other person do a great deal of the talking.&lt;/strong&gt;  This approach handles complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Let the other person feel that the idea is his or hers.&lt;/strong&gt; Or as I’d like to say it: Make the other person feel involved – which raises his importance.  This will get their cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Try honestly to see things from the other person’s point of view.&lt;/strong&gt; It does wonders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Be Sympathetic with the other person’s ideas and desires.&lt;/strong&gt;  It’s what every person wants.  And this rule is similar to seeing the other person’s point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Appeal to the nobler motives.&lt;/strong&gt;  An appeal that everybody likes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11.  Dramatize your ideas.&lt;/strong&gt;  Facts are not enough; dramatization matters.  Art &amp;amp; Movies do it so should you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. Throw down a challenge.&lt;/strong&gt;  When nothing else works, throwing a challenge is the last resort.  The desire to excel is the fire that motivates everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The way to get things done,”&lt;/em&gt; say Schwab, &lt;em&gt;“is to stimulate competition. I do not mean in a sordid, money-getting way, but in the desire to excel.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;That is what every successful person loves: the game. The chance for self-expression. The chance to prove his or her worth, to excel, to win. That is what makes foot races and hog-calling and pie-eating contests. The desire to excel. The desire for a feeling of importance.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 06:43:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/interact/2014/01/30/win-people/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/interact/2014/01/30/win-people/</guid>
        
        
        <category>interact</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ways to Make People Like You</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/4XZxFdh.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing-small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Dale Carnegie’s &lt;em&gt;“How to Win Friends and Influence People,”&lt;/em&gt; Carnegie provided 3 principles on ways to make people like you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Become genuinely interested in other people.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;em&gt;“Do this and you’ll be welcomed anywhere.”&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When dealing with others, be interested in them as a dog would be interested in you.  Greet people with animation and enthusiasm like &lt;em&gt;Kareem&lt;/em&gt;  would.  You can make more friends in 2 months by becoming interested in other people than in 2 years by trying to get other people interested in you.  People are not interested in you. They are not interested in me. They are interested in themselves - morning, noon and after dinner (and there is nothing wrong with that; it’s human nature).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we merely try to impress people and get people interested in us, we will never have many true, sincere friends. Friends, real friends, are not made that way.  Alfred Adler, the famous Viennese psychologist, wrote in his book: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;It is the individual who is not interested in his fellow men who has the greatest difficulties in life and provides the greatest injury to others. It is from among such individuals that all human failures spring.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And be grateful.  A magician once said, “I am grateful because these people come to see me, They make it possible for me to make my living in a very agreeable way. I’m going to give them the very best I possibly can.”  A show of interest, as with every other principle of human relations, must be sincere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Smile.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;“A simple way to make a good first impression.”&lt;/em&gt;  A warm genuine smile signals that you’re grateful for their attention and presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, I do feel there’s a boundary between a warm genuine smile and too much smile.  Try smirking if unsure of this boundary (usually more suited for guys).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Remember that a person’s name is to that person the sweetest and most important sound in any language.&lt;/strong&gt;  Damn right it is.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Be a good listener.  Encourage others to talk about themselves.&lt;/strong&gt;  This is &lt;em&gt;“the easiest way to become a good conversationalist”&lt;/em&gt;.  Knowing to keep mum also helps you to prevent from kicking the beehive.  The lesson here is that a person’s toothache means more to that person than a famine in China.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Talk in terms of the other person’s interest.&lt;/strong&gt; How to interest people?  You must know how to talk in their interest – this in turn will enthuse them.  In addition, it’s like foreplay in sex or dynamic-stretching in weightlifting, you need to warm up first to achieve fun/great results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Make the other person feel important – and do it sincerely.&lt;/strong&gt;  This is probably the weakest principle in this list.  I believe that once you start listening to the other person, are interested in him, and call him by his name, you have then made him feel important in a sincere manner.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 06:43:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/interact/2014/01/29/ways-to-make-people-like-you/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/interact/2014/01/29/ways-to-make-people-like-you/</guid>
        
        
        <category>interact</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Principle 3: Make Them See the Fire!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/X88bB9P.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing-small&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to make a person do something for you is by arousing in them the desire/fire to accomplish it for themselves.  Sure, placing fire under one’s ass would get the other person moving too, but that person would only work until his skin is at a good distance from the flame. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always think about ourselves.  When we look at a a group photo, the first face we look at is ourselves [p62].  When we talk in a conversation, the part we enjoy the most is when we talk about ourselves.  So when influencing the other person, Why talk about what we want? That is childish. Of course, you are interested in what you want. You are eternally interested in it. But no one else is. The rest of us are just like you: we are interested in what we want.
So the only way on earth to influence other people is to talk about what they want and show them how to get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most effective way to deal with people is – an increased tendency to think always in terms of other people’s point of view, and see things from their angle. Looking at the other person’s point of view and arousing in him an eager want for something is not to be construed as manipulating that person so that he will do something that is only for your benefit and his detriment. Each party should gain from the negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“First, arouse in the other person an eager want He who can do this has the whole world with him. He who cannot walks a lonely way.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 06:43:59 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>www.anton23.com/interact/2014/01/28/see-the-fire/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">www.anton23.com/interact/2014/01/28/see-the-fire/</guid>
        
        
        <category>interact</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
